A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Women's Health Program, SG 1, Series 38 FA782
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Women's Health Program, SG 1, Series 38
1994-2001
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA782
8.74 Cubic Feet 23 document boxes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund collection was donated to the RAC in 1985. Records in this series were transferred to the RAC by Commonwealth Fund in 1999.
Arrangement
Arrangement: As received.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Biographical / Historical
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
Scope and Contents
Significant records in this series include the Adolescent Girls Health Study of 1997 and the Commonwealth Fund's second Women's Study of 1999.
The series also contains Women's Health Program staff files including program staff administrative documentation of select grants from 1994-1999, as well as associated symposiums, briefings and select Commission on Women's Health meetings.
- Commonwealth Fund records, Women's Health Program, 1994-2001; 38
  - Adolescent Girls Health Study - Summary, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adolescent Girls Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls Only - Banner by Banner and Banner 1, 1997 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adolescent Girls Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls Only - Banner 2 and 3, 1997 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls Only - Banner 4 and 5, 1997 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Revised Smoker and Drinker Banner Points - Girls Only - Banner by Banner and Banner 5, 1997 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls Only - Banner 6 and 7, 1997 July 2 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Boys Only - Banner by Banner and Banner 1, 1997 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Boys Only - Banner 2 and 3, 1997 July 3 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Boys Only - Banner 4 and 5, 1997 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Revised Smoker and Drinker Banner Points - Boys Only - Banner by Banner and Banner 5, 1997 September 8 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Boys Only - Banner 6 and 7, 1997 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls and Boys - Banner by Banner and Banner 1, 1997 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls and Boys - Banner 2 and 3, 1997 July 3 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls and Boys - Banner 4 and 5, 1997 July 3 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
  - Adolescent Health Study - Final Tabulations - Girls and Boys - Banner 6 and 7, 1997 July 3 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Women's Health Study II - Tabulations Summary, 1999 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 1 - Women - Demographics 1, 1999 January (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 2 - Women - Demographics 2, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 3 - Women - Health Care 1, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 4 - Women - Health Insurance, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 5 - Women - Violence, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 6 - Women - Health Behaviors, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 7 - Women - Health Care Utilization, 1999 January (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner X, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 1 - Men - Demographics 1, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 2 - Men - Demographics 2, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 3 - Men - Health Care 1, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 4 - Men - Health Insurance, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 5 - Men - Health Behaviors, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Women's Health Study II - Final Tabulations - Banner 6 - Men - Health Care Utilization, 1999 January (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Adolescent Girls Health Study - Book - Contracts with Authors, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Improving the Health of Adolescent Girls - Policy Report of the Commonwealth Fund Commission on Women's Health, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Women's Health Symposium - Invite Lists and Attendance (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Women's Health Symposium - Transcript, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Commission on Women's Health Meeting, Washington, DC, 1998 November 12 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Adolescent Girls Health Symposium Video, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Adolescent Girls Health Symposium Video - Release Form, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Resticted from scholarly access - confidential material.
  - Commission on Women's Health - Paper - Contract, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Legends to Live By - Public Education Campaign to Promote Women's Health, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Commission on Women's Health Meeting (October 1996), Carter Presidential Library, Atlanta, GA - Briefing Book and Drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Commission on Women's Health Meeting (October 1996), Carter Presidential Library, Atlanta, GA - Briefing Book and Drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 52-54)
  - Commission on Women's Health Meeting, New York City - Briefing Book Draft, 1997 April (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Health of Adolescent Girls Symposium, New York City - Briefing Book Draft, 1997 April (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Commission on Women's Health Meeting, Washington, DC - Briefing Book Draft and Policy Report, 1998 January (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Society for the Advancement of Women's Health Research Conference (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 59-60)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Analysis - General, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 61-62)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Analysis - Literature Review, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Analysis - Fact Sheets, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Meetings and Data, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 65-66)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Focus Groups, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Background Experts, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Articles and Background, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Proposals, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Domestic Violence Symposium (Grant 95447) - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Outside Reviewers, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448), 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 73-74)
  - Survey of the Health of Adolescent Girls (Grant 95448) - Charts, Tables, Findings, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 75-76)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Administrative, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Readings (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Bristol Myers Squibb, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Grant Products (Box 12, Folder 81-82)
  - American Medical Women's Association Foundation - McGrath - Planning a Women's Guide to Health Care Decisionmaking (Grant 94-85) - Phase II, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Administrative, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Readings (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Proposal, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 87-88)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - New York Urban League - Garfield - Violence in the Lives of NYC African-American Women and Adolescent Girts (Grant 94-86) - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 90-91)
  - American Medical Association Education and Research Foundation - Goldman - Community Guide on Family Violence (Grant 95042), 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - American Medical Association Education and Research Foundation - Goldman - Community Guide on Family Violence (Grant 95042) - Administrative, 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - American Medical Association Education and Research Foundation - Goldman - Community Guide on Family Violence (Grant 95042) - Articles (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - American Medical Association Education and Research Foundation - Goldman - Community Guide on Family Violence (Grant 95042) - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - American Medical Association Education and Research Foundation - Goldman - Community Guide on Family Violence (Grant 95042) - Grant Products, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 94-84) - Administrative, 1994-1999 (Box 15, Folder 97-98)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 94-84) - Correspondence and Meetings, 1994-1997 (Box 15, Folder 99)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 94-84) - Chart Book, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 100-101)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 94-84) - Grant Products, 1994-1998 (Box 16, Folder 102-103)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Delivering Preventive Services to Women at Risk - Phase II (Grant 95-15), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Delivering Preventive Services to Women at Risk - Phase II (Grant 95-15) - Administrative, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 105)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Delivering Preventive Services to Women at Risk - Phase II (Grant 95-15) - Readings (Box 16, Folder 106)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Delivering Preventive Services to Women at Risk - Phase II (Grant 95-15) - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 107-108)
  - Columbia University Health Sciences Division - Blustein - Access to Primary Care for Older Women and Minorities (Grant 95-16) - Administrative, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 109)
  - Columbia University Health Sciences Division - Blustein - Access to Primary Care for Older Women and Minorities (Grant 95-16) - Readings (Box 17, Folder 110)
  - Columbia University Health Sciences Division - Blustein - Access to Primary Care for Older Women and Minorities (Grant 95-16) - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 111)
  - Columbia University Health Sciences Division - Blustein - Access to Primary Care for Older Women and Minorities (Grant 95-16) - Grant Products, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 112-113)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute - Krimgold - Mental Health and Access to Care (Grant 95-40) - Administrative, 1994-1997 (Box 17, Folder 114)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute - Krimgold - Mental Health and Access to Care (Grant 95-40) - Readings (Box 17, Folder 115)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute - Krimgold - Mental Health and Access to Care (Grant 95-40) - Proposal, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 116)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute - Krimgold - Mental Health and Access to Care (Grant 95-40) - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 117)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 95413) - Administration, 1994-1998 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 95413) - Proposal, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - Columbia University - Leiman - Administration of the Commission on Women's Heath (Grant 95413) - Grant Products, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Symposium, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 121-122)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 124)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 19, Folder 125-128)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Administration, 1995-1997 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Mathematica Policy Research - St. Peter - Improving the Provision of Clinical Preventive Services for Women in HMOs (Grant 96179) - Editorial, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Mathematica Policy Research (PDF 95889), 1995 (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Administration, 1996-1998 (Box 20, Folder 132)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Articles (Box 20, Folder 133)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Proposal, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 134)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 20, Folder 135)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Grant Products, 1996-1998 (Box 20, Folder 136)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 1, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 137)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 2, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 138)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 3, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 139)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 4, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 140)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 5, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 141)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 6, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 142)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 7, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 143)
  - Jacobs Institute - Romans - Defining Issues and Monitoring Trends in Women's Health and Managed Care (Grant 96349) - Briefing 8, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 144)
  - Rand Corporation - Farley - Women's Health Insurance (Grant 96007) - Adminstration, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 145)
  - Rand Corporation - Farley - Women's Health Insurance (Grant 96007) - Articles (Box 21, Folder 146)
  - Rand Corporation - Farley - Women's Health Insurance (Grant 96007) - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 21, Folder 147)
  - Rand Corporation - Farley - Women's Health Insurance (Grant 96007) - Grant Products, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 148-150)
  - Falik-MD5 Associates - (Grant 98509) - Analysis of the 1998 Survey of Women's Health, 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 151-155)